After installing git you may want to change
some of your profile settings.
Most of the time they are in the home directory in the ".profile" file
or any similar file that your shell is using.
Heres an example:
First environment variable is setting the language for git messages
One can use LC_MESSAGES or LANGUAGE.
I've set mine to english.
The rest of this file contains command line settings.
You can, of course, skip it if you want to start working with git immediately.
This script [git-completion.bash] mostly goes as a part of a git install
and sets the autocompletion for the git console commands.
I have it here, and you, most likely, will have it in some other location.
But even if you dont have it, you can download it from here.
And this script "git-prompt.sh" is in the same place
and it contains a git_ps1 function that allows us to add various useful info
about the state of the git project to the command prompt
These 2 environment variables
[GIT_PS1_SHOWDIRTYSTATE=true GIT_PS!_SHOWUNTRACKEDFILES=true]
are not mandatory, but they are also declared and used in this file.
These are the most basic settings.
There are plenty of other,
way more powerful scripts for efficient command line and git integration,
written by the 3rd party developers.
They are easy to find,
just google "git prompt" and your shell name
like bash or zsh or any other
And you will see dozens of results.
But you may not want to spend your time on that right now. First, watch the screencast and get a better understanding of git.
Right after that I highly recommend you to install this kind of script as it can be extremely helpful.
In this screencast I use a bash script
that you can find here [https://github.magicmonty/bash-git-prompt]
but most of the time all the scripts are quite similar,
therefore pick the one you like, whichever fits you best.